Guide to the Dramatic Museum Realia,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Dramatic Museum Realia,
[18th c.]-1966.
Columbia University. Brander Matthews Dramatic Museum.
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
7818783
This collection contains puppets, masks, and set models from the collection of the Brander Matthews Dramatic Museum and Library.
Historical Note
Brander Matthews (1852-1929) first began collecting puppets in 1867 at the age of sixteen, when on his first trip to France he bought a set of eleven Guignol hand puppets with wooden heads. His puppet collection, along with the various stage models and masks he had collected over the years, eventually became part of the Dramatic Museum, which opened in 1911.
After Matthew's death, the Museum's curators continued to expand the collections, and created an inventory of the puppets and masks in the 1960s.
When the museum was dissolved in 1971, the puppets and masks were transferred first to the Art Properties Department, and then to the Rare Book and Manuscript Library in 1981 & 1983, where they remain. The set models were first on long-term loan to Barnard, and then most were for many years on display in Dodge Hall; they were transferred to Art Properties in 1996, then to RBML in 2001. Many pieces included in the Museum's 1960s inventories are no longer in the collection. Only the remaining items are described in this finding aid.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the three-dimensional objects which once belonged to the Columbia University Brander Matthews Dramatic Museum. Founded in 1911, the Brander Matthews Dramatic Museum and Library contained books and manuscripts; prints, paintings and photographs of theatre artists; posters, programs, and playbills, among other artifacts. It was the museum’s extensive collection of models, masks, and puppets, however, which was truly emblematic of Matthews’ distinctive vision of the theatre, a vision centered not just in dramatic literature, but in the theatre experience as a whole (Bell 2004). Gathered for documentary and pedagogical purposes, the objects range in date from the 18th well into the 20th centuries, and are from countries all around the globe. The collection is now organized by format: puppets; masks; and set models and theater models (the first category includes dolls, figurines, and some miscellaneous materials). This unique collection of artifacts is the legacy of a man who championed the inclusion of such objects in any legitimate history of the theatre.
This collection contains 391 puppets, 128 masks, and 30 stage models.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in three series
Series I: Puppets
Subseries I.1: Burma
Subseries 1.2: China
Subseries 1.3: England
Subseries I.3: France
Subseries I.4: Ghana
Subseries I.5: India
Subseries I.6: Indonesia
Subseries I.7: Italy
Subseries I.8: Japan
Subseries I.9: Russia
Subseries I.10: Thailand
Subseries I.11: Turkey
Subseries I.12: United States
Subseries I.13: Unknown Origin
Series II: Masks
Subseries II.1: Africa
Subseries II.2: Congo
Subseries II.3: Gabon
Subseries II.4: Guatemala
Subseries II.5: Indonesia
Subseries II.6: Italy
Subseries II.7: Ivory Coast
Subseries II.8: Japan
Subseries II.9: Liberia
Subseries II.10: Mexico
Subseries II.11: New Guinea
Subseries II.12: Nigeria
Subseries II.13: North America
Subseries II.14: Sri Lanka
Subseries II.15: Thailand
Subseries II.16: United States
Subseries II.17: Zaire
Series III: Stage Models
Subseries III.1: Historical Models
Subseries III.2: Set Models
Subjects
Jones, Robert Edmond, 1887-1954.; Bufano, Remo.; Matthews, Brander, 1852-1929.; Museums--New York (State)--New York.; Theater.; Dioramas.; Dolls.; Figurines; Hand puppets.; Historical model.; Marionettes (stringed puppets).; Masks (costume).; Pantins.; Puppets (recreational artifacts).; Rod puppets.; Shadow puppets; Textiles
Access Restrictions
This collection is located on-site.
Some of the items are fragile and their use may be restricted. The larger items (models and some puppets) can only be seen by appointment. These restrictions are included in the descriptions of the individual items, below.
Related Material-- at Columbia
Dramatic Museum Ephemera Columbia University Rare Book & Manuscript Library
The Dramatic Museum Ephemera Colelction contains posters, playbills, programs, subject files and portraits once part of the Brander Matthews Dramatic Museum.
Dramatic Library Manuscript Collection 1864-1911 Columbia University Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Dramatic Library Manuscript Collection 1864-1911 contains a collection of letters and manuscripts that formed part of the collection of the Dramatic Museum
Columbia University Brander Matthews Dramatic Museum Collection Columbia Rare Book & Manuscript Library
These are the records of the Dramatic Museum itself, and contain much information on the acquisition of the Realia.
Joseph Urban Papers, 1893-1998 Columbia University Rare Book & Manuscript Library
The Joseph Urban Papers, which were originally acquired by the Brander Matthews Dramatic Museum and are now held by RBML, contain a large number of set models created by Urban’s studio.
Other materials from the Brander Matthews Dramatic Museum are in the Office of Art Properties (art objects such as puppets and masks); Barnard's Minor Latham Theatre (stage and theater models); Barnard Library (phonograph records - 33 1/3 rpm); and the Music Library (music phonograph records).
- Series I: Puppets
  This collection now contains 391 objects; mostly puppets, including marionettes, hand puppets, rod puppets, pantins, and shadow puppets, but also a number of figurines, dolls and dioramas, and three textiles. It appears that non-puppet three-dimensional objects were included in the puppet series before 1971. The puppets were assigned identification numbers during a cataloging project in the 1960s. All puppet identification numbers higher than P69 were assigned in 2009.
  The earliest acquisitions were gifts of Brander Matthews. The most recent acquisitions, and also the collection’s newest items, are three beggar figurines made by Russian émigrés living in Iran during WWII. They were the gift of Majorie Windust Halper in 1989.
  What began as a collection of English, French and Italian puppets gradually became a collection of considerable breadth, with puppets from Burma, China, India, the United States, Thailand, Turkey, Java, Japan, and Mexico, among other countries. The oldest puppets are two 18th century French marionettes of Joseph and one of the Magi. Highlights of the collection include two eight-foot tall puppets designed by Robert Edmond Jones and constructed by American theatre pioneer Remo Bufano for the Metropolitan Opera’s 1931 production of Stravinsky’s Oedipus Rex.
  - Suberies I.1: Burma
    - P20 Accession
      - Burmese marionette of male with white face and red robe, P20.01 (Box 1)
      - Burmese marionette of male with white face and sand-colored robe, P20.02 (Box 1)
      - Burmese marionette of male with flesh-colored face, P20.03 (Box 1)
      - Horse marionette, P20.04 (Box 38)
  - Subseries I.2: China
    - P14 Accession
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.01 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.02 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.03 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.04 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.05 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.06 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.07 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.08 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.09 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.10 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.11 (Box 26)
      - Chinese Shadow puppet, P14.12 (Box 26)
    - P15 Accession
      - Chinese jigging puppet of male with pink face, P15.02 (Box 3)
      - Chinese jigging puppet of male with pink face, P15.03 (Box 3)
      - Chinese jigging puppet of male with pink face, P15.04 (Box 3)
      - Chinese jigging puppet of male with pink-white face, P15.05 (Box 3)
      - Chinese jigging puppet of female with white face, P15.06 (Box 3)
      - Chinese jigging puppet of male with white face, P15.07 (Box 3)
      - Chinese jigging puppet of male with pink face, P15.09 (Box 3)
      - Chinese jigging puppet of male with stylized makeup, P15.10 (Box 3)
    - P24 Accession
      - Chinese female Figurine with red robe and white, painted face, P24.01 (Box 35)
      - Chinese Figurine, missing head, with purple robe, P24.02 (Box 35)
      - Chinese female Figurine with green robe and white, painted face, P24.03 (Box 35)
      - Chinese female Figurines with long, red dress and elaborate headdress, P24.04 (Box 35)
      - Chinese Figurine, missing head, with long, red dress, P24.05 (Box 36)
      - Chinese female Figurine with long, red dress and white,painted face, P24.06 (Box 36)
      - Chinese male Figurine with orange robe and long mustache, P24.07 (Box 36)
      - Chinese male Figurine with long, green robe, P24.08 (Box 36)
      - Chinese male Figurine, missing head, in gray robe over red robe, P24.09 (Box 37)
      - Chinese male Figurine, bald and in light green robe, P24.10 (Box 37)
      - Masked Chinese male Figurine with headdress and striped pants, P24.11 (Box 37)
      - Masked Chinese male Figurine with long beard and striped pants, P24.12 (Box 37)
      - Crown for Chinese Figurine, P24.13A (Box 35)
      - Crown for Chinese Figurine, P24.13B (Box 35)
      - Crown for Chinese Figurine, P24.13C (Box 35)
      - Crown for Chinese Figurine, P24.13D (Box 35)
      - Man's head from a Chinese figurine, P24.13E (Box 35)
      - Woman's head from a Chinese figurine, P24.13F (Box 35)
      - Woman's head from a Chinese figurine, P24.13G (Box 35)
    - P26 Accession
      - Female Peking Opera figurine in black, P26.01 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with white, painted face and blue, striped pants, P26.02 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine in green robes and gold headdress, P26.03 (Box 39)
      - Female Peking Opera figurine in pink and blue with elaborate headdress, P26.04 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with long ponytail, P26.05 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with staff and yellow and green hat, P26.06 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine in blue and white headress, fighting, P26.07 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine in black with silver staff, P26.08 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with long heard, arm raised, fighting, P26.09 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with long beard and dark blue robe, P26.10 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with painted face and very elaborate headress, P26.11 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with painted face, two feathers on headdress, P26.12 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with orange and white face, gold hat, P26.13 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine in green robe, blue, orange and white face, P26.14 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with weapon on back, P26.15 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with with red face and green robe, P26.16 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with red, white, black face and gold headdress, P26.17 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with blue headdress and green robe, P26.18 (Box 39)
      - Male Peking Opera figurine with long beard in yellow and orange, P26.19 (Box 39)
    - P57 Accession
      - Han Chung-Li figurine, P57.01 (Box 8)
      - Tsao Kuo-Shin figurine, P57.02 (Box 8)
      - Chang Kuo-Lao figurine, P57.03 (Box 8)
      - Lu Tung-Pin figurine, P57.04 (Box 8)
      - Li The-Kwai figurine, P57.05 (Box 8)
      - Lan Tsai-Ho figurine, P57.06 (Box 8)
      - Tsao Kuo-Shin figurine, duplicate of P57.2, P57.07 (Box 8)
    - P60 Accession
      - Figurine in Imperial dress, P60.01 (Box 28)
    - P70 Accession
      - Miniature diorama, P70.01 (Box 28)
      - Miniature diorama, P70.02 (Box 28)
      - Miniature diorama, P70.03 (Box 28)
      - Miniature diorama, P70.04 (Box 28)
      - Miniature diorama, P70.05 (Box 28)
      - Miniature diorama, P70.06 (Box 28)
  - Subseries I.3: England
    - P04 Accession
      - Milkmaid marionette with yoke and two pails, P04.01 (Box 1)
      - Male marionette in exotic yellow costume, P04.02 (Box 2)
    - P32 Accession
      - Robin Hood pantin, P32.01 (Box 24)
      - Nigger pantin, P32.02 (Box 24)
      - Female Volunteer pantin, P32.03 (Box 24)
      - Maid Marian pantin, P32.04 (Box 24)
      - Lord Dundreary pantin, P32.05 (Box 24)
      - Robin Hood pantin, P32.06 (Box 24)
      - The Magic Nigger pantin, P32.07 (Box 24)
      - Jester pantin, P32.08 (Box 24)
      - Merry Andrew pantin, P32.09 (Box 24)
  - Subseries I.4: France
    - P05 Accession
      - Housemaid marionette, 1870-1899; P05.02 (Box 50)
      - Jester marionette, 1870-1899; P05.03 (Box 4)
      - Dog marionette, 1870-1899; P05.06 (Box 4)
      - Female marionette with four children in her pockets, 1870-1899; P05.07 (Box 5)
      - Peg-leg sailor marionette with fiddle and bow, P05.08 (Box 6)
      - Elegant eighteenth-century female marionette, 1870-1899; P05.09 (Box 7)
    - P06 Accession
      - Saint Joseph marionette, 1800-1899; P06.01 (Box 7)
      - Marionette of one of the Magi, 1800-1899; P06.02 (Box 7)
    - P07 Accession
      - Wood ledge puppet of an eighteenth century man, 1800-1899; P07.01 (Box 22)
    - P08 Accession
      - Male hand puppet with green hat, P08.02 (Box 9)
      - Old, bald male hand puppet, P08.03 (Box 10)
      - Nurse hand puppet, P08.04 (Box 9)
      - Male hand puppet with mustache and bicorne hat, P08.05 (Box 9)
      - Black devil hand puppet, P08.08 (Box 10)
      - Hand puppet with red scarf, P08.09 (Box 10)
      - Male hand puppet with missing tooth, P08.10 (Box 10)
      - Female hand puppet with kerchief and purple scarf, P08.11 (Box 10)
      - Female hand puppet with kerchief and brown scarf, P08.12 (Box 10)
      - Male hand puppet with purple clothes, P08.13 (Box 10)
      - Bearded male hand puppet with green scarf, P08.14 (Box 10)
    - P09 Accession
      - Male hand puppet with green cap, P09.01 (Box 11)
      - Green and orange devil hand puppet, P09.02 (Box 11)
      - Male hand puppet in white vest with black bird print, P09.03 (Box 12)
      - Elderly male hand puppet with long nose, green cap, eyeglasses, P09.04 (Box 11)
      - Female hand puppet with black and white dress and white apron, P09.05 (Box 12)
      - Chef hand puppet, P09.06 (Box 13)
      - Female hand puppet with white, red dress and blue, white apron, P09.07 (Box 12)
      - Male hand puppet with bicorne hat, P09.08 (Box 11)
      - Clown hand puppet dressed in white and red, P09.09 (Box 13)
      - Male head of hand puppet, P09.10 (Box 13)
      - Male hand puppet with red and blue hat, P09.11 (Box 12)
      - Male hand puppet with white and gold vest, blue coat, P09.12 (Box 13)
      - Elderly male hand puppet with long nose, green cap, eyeglasses, P09.13 (Box 12)
      - Female hand puppet with blue ribbon around neck, P09.14 (Box 14)
      - Green and orange devil hand puppet, P09.15 (Box 13)
      - Bald hand puppet in blue flower print robe, P09.16 (Box 14)
      - Male hand puppet with black hair and blue robe, P09.17 (Box 14)
      - male hand puppet with red and blue hat, protruding stomach, P09.18 (Box 9)
      - Head of bald male hand puppet, with brown glass eyes, P09.19 (Box 15)
      - Head of a clown hand puppet, with face painted white, red and black, P09.20 (Box 15)
      - Head of a hand puppet, with blue cap and long nose, P09.21 (Box 15)
      - Head of male hand puppet with mustache and bicorne hat worn front-to-back, P09.22 (Box 15)
      - Head of male hand puppet with mutton chops and bicorne hat worn side-to-side, P09.23 (Box 15)
      - Head of male hand puppet with dark eyes and a painted moustache, P09.24 (Box 15)
      - Head of male hand puppet with dark eyes and a small painted beard, P09.25 (Box 15)
      - Head of male hand puppet with wig, rosy face, painted moustache, P09.26 (Box 15)
      - Head of hand puppet with wig, painted moustache and beard, P09.27 (Box 15)
      - Crocodile hand puppet, P09.30 (Box 14)
      - Face for a hand puppet, P09.31 (Box 15)
      - Face for a hand puppet, P09.32 (Box 15)
      - Face for a hand puppet, P09.33 (Box 15)
      - Face for a hand puppet, P09.34 (Box 15)
    - P10 Accession
      - Picket fence shadow puppet, P10.01 (Box 16)
      - Running dog shadow puppet, P10.02 (Box 16)
      - Bare tree shadow puppet, P10.03 (Box 16)
      - Head with hinged jaw shadow puppet, P10.04 (Box 16)
      - Seal and unattached rod from a shadow puppet, P10.05 (Box 16)
      - Ballerina shadow puppet, P10.06 (Box 16)
      - Monkey shadow puppet, P10.07 (Box 16)
      - Man with fuzzy hair shadow puppet, P10.08 (Box 16)
      - Running man shadow puppet, P10.09 (Box 16)
      - Table with purse shadow puppet, P10.10 (Box 16)
      - Boat with rudder shadow puppet, P10.11 (Box 16)
      - Profile of person with hinged arm shadow puppet, P10.12 (Box 16)
      - Donkey shadow puppet, P10.13 (Box 17)
      - Large bird shadow puppet, P10.14 (Box 17)
      - Butterfly shadow puppet, P10.15 (Box 17)
      - Fisherman and fish shadow puppet, P10.16 (Box 17)
      - Large head with hinged jaw shadow puppet, P10.17 (Box 17)
      - Man with hat and whip shadow puppet, P10.18 (Box 17)
      - Man with fork shadow puppet, P10.19 (Box 17)
      - Small bird shadow puppet, P10.20 (Box 17)
      - Bull shadow puppet, P10.21 (Box 17)
      - Cat shadow puppet, P10.22 (Box 17)
      - Fence shadow puppet, P10.23 (Box 17)
      - Boat with wheel and two sails shadow puppet, P10.25 (Box 18)
      - Sailboat with sails attached shadow puppet, P10.26 (Box 18)
      - Sailboat shadow puppet, P10.27 (Box 18)
      - Large boat with potholes and netting shadow puppet, P10.28 (Box 18)
      - Large sailboat marked C12 shadow puppet, P10.29 (Box 19)
      - Large sailboat marked C10 shadow puppet, P10.30 (Box 19)
      - Small sailboat marked C8 shadow puppet, P10.31 (Box 19)
      - Steamship shadow puppet, P10.32 (Box 19)
    - P43 Accession
      - Ombre chinoise, female dancer, P43.01 (Box 24)
      - Ombre chinoise, female dancer, P43.02 (Box 24)
    - P44 Accession
      - Toutatoua Prix de Beaute d'Afrique doll, P44.01 (Box 34)
      - Tah-Dhor Prix de Beaute d'Asie doll, P44.02 (Box 34)
      - Latin female doll, P44.03 (Box 34)
      - Greek or Russian male doll, P44.04 (Box 34)
      - Chinese female doll, P44.05 (Box 34)
      - Chinese female doll, P44.06 (Box 34)
  - Subseries I.5: Ghana
    - P50 Accession
      - African rod puppet, P50.02 (Box 46)
  - Subseries I.6: India
    - P42 Accession
      - Green worm or fish rod puppet, P42.01 (Box 45)
      - Elephant rod puppet, P42.02 (Box 45)
      - Horse rod puppet, P42.03 (Box 45)
      - Horse and chariot rod puppet, P42.04 (Box 45)
      - Rooster rod puppet, P42.05 (Box 45)
      - Yellow [goat] rod puppet, P42.06 (Box 45)
      - Bull rod puppet, P42.07 (Box 45)
    - P51 Accession
      - Rama shadow puppet, P51.01 (Box TSP33)
      - Lakshmana shadow puppet, P51.02 (Box TSP25)
      - Sita, shadow puppet, P51.03 (Box TSP38)
      - Rakshana, shadow puppet, P51.04 (Box TSP35)
      - Supanaka, shadow puppet, P51.05 (Box TSP37)
      - Head of Dasa Kanta Ravana, shadow puppet, P51.06a (Box TSP41)
      - Body of Dasa Kanta Ravana, shadow puppet, P51.06b (Box TSP32)
    - P52 Accession
      - Indian shadow puppet, P52.01 (Box TSP26)
      - Indian shadow puppet, P52.02 (Box TSP27)
      - Indian shadow puppet, P52.03 (Box TSP28)
      - Indian shadow puppet; on horse, P52.04 (Box TSP29)
      - Indian shadow puppet, P52.05 (Box TSP30)
      - Indian shadow puppet, P52.06 (Box TSP31)
      - Indian shadow puppet, P52.07 (Box TSP34)
      - Indian shadow puppet, P52.08 (Box TSP36)
      - Indian shadow puppet, P52.09 (Box TSP39)
    - TSP Accession
      - Indian shadow puppet, TSP40 (Box TSP40)
  - Subseries I.7: Indonesia
    - P18 Accession
      - Wajang Golek rod puppet with light yellow face, P18.01 (Box 31)
      - 2 upper arms and 2 lower arms from Wajang Golek puppet P18.2, P18.02 (Box 32)
      - Wajang Golek rod puppet with orange/pink face, P18.02 (Box 31)
      - Wajang Golek rod puppet with white face, P18.03 (Box 33)
    - P39 Accession
      - Wajang golek rod puppet, P39.01 (Box 32)
      - Wajang golek rod puppet with red face, P39.02 (Box 33)
      - Wajang golek rod puppet, P39.03 (Box 32)
      - Wajang golek rod puppet, P39.04 (Box 32)
    - P80s Accession
      - Wayang puppet, P81 (Box 30)
      - Wayang puppet, P82 (Box 30)
      - Arm of missing Wayang Golek rod puppet, P84 (Box 32)
      - Six rods for Wayang Golek rod puppets, P85 (Box 32)
      - Two wings for Wayang Golek rod puppet, P86 (Box 32)
  - Subseries I.8: Italy
    - P11 Accession
      - Arlecchino marionette, P11.01 (Box 20)
      - Arlecchino marionette, P11.02 (Box 21)
      - Brighella marionette, P11.03 (Box 20)
      - Pantalone marionette, P11.04 (Box 20)
      - Il Dottore marionette, P11.05 (Box 20)
      - Marionette of figure in white with black mask, P11.06 (Box 20)
      - Marionette of figure in white with black mask, P11.07 (Box 20)
      - Marionette of red-headed male in white with black cap and buttons, P11.08 (Box 20)
      - Marionette of female in white with black buttons, P11.09 (Box 21)
      - Skeleton marionette, P11.11 (Box 21)
      - Marionette of red-headed king, P11.12 (Box 21)
      - Marionette of queen in red dress, P11.13 (Box 21)
      - Marionette of boy in tricorne hat, P11.14 (Box 21)
      - Marionette of maid in black with white apron, P11.15 (Box 21)
      - Marionette of young girl with blue flowers in hair, P11.16 (Box 21)
      - Marionette of old woman with red ribbon around neck, P11.18 (Box 21)
    - P12 Accession
      - Orlando rod puppet, 1875-1900; P12.01 (Box 27)
      - Rinaldo rod puppet, 1875-1900; P12.02 (Box 27)
    - P33 Accession
      - Rinaldo, 1900-1960; P33.01 (Box 27)
    - P34 Accession
      - Sicilian rod puppet with cross on armor and shield, P34.01 (Box 43)
      - Sicilian rod puppet with bird on armor and shield, P34.02 (Box 44)
  - Subseries I.9: Japan
    - P16 Accession
      - Japanese female marionette, P16.01 (Box 25)
    - P17 Accession
      - Japanese rod puppet, 1800-1899; P17.01 (Box 42)
    - P27 Accession
      - Little man marionette, P27.01 (Box 42)
      - Lion / Dragon marionette, P27.02 (Box 42)
    - P28 Accession
      - Small mask of elderly man with beard, P28.01 (Box 42)
      - Small mask of elderly woman, P28.02 (Box 42)
      - Small mask of young woman, P28.03 (Box 42)
    - P37 Accession
      - Japanese wig for a puppet, P37.01 (Box 22)
      - Japanese wig for a puppet, P37.01 (Box 22)
    - P38 Accession
      - Figurine with set of hair dressings of Japanese women artistically arranged in several forms, P38.01 (Box 22)
    - P46 Accession
      - Clothed figure or doll of Shio-Kumi, P46.01 (Box 53)
    - P56 Accession
      - Figurine on stand of male with cloth covering face, P56.01 (Box 47)
      - Figurine on stand of male in black, holding scroll, P56.02 (Box 47)
      - Figurine on stand of male in black, holding scroll, P56.03 (Box 47)
      - Figurine on stand of male, fighting, painted white, P56.04 (Box 47)
      - Figurine on stand of male, fighting, painted white, P56.05 (Box 47)
      - FMusic stand with instruments, P56.06 (Box 47)
      - Music stand with instruments, P56.07 (Box 47)
      - Banner on stand with Japanese characters, P56.08 (Box 47)
      - Banner on stand with Japanese characters, P56.09 (Box 47)
      - Banner on stand with Japanese characters, P56.10 (Box 47)
      - Banner on stand with Japanese characters, P56.11 (Box 47)